<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
    <name>Bleb march magic items</name>
        <description>magic items that are being used in bleb march</description>
        <author url="">Mist Helix</author>
        <update version="0.0.18">
            <file name="MistMagic.xml"
            url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MistHelix/MistMagic-items/main/MistMagic.xml"/>
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="Mystical Cigar" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_MistHelix_HomeBrew_MAGIC_ITEM_MYSTICAL_CIGAR">
		<description>
			<p>If you smoke one of these it takes your concentration and an action. When begin to smoke you flip a coin if its head it casts fog cloud 60ft range and lasts for 3 rounds and is consumbed. If you flipped tails you cast disguise self where your disguise must include someone smoking a cigar. It lasts for one minute.</p>
			
		</description>
		<setters>
			
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="rarity">common</set>
			
			
		</setters>
	</element>
    <element name="Dvorak's Research" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_TUNA_HomeBrew_MAGIC_ITEM_DVORAK'S_RESEARCH">
        <description>
            <p> Some would kill for a chance to read this grimoire, and the tome itself will kill many readers.</p>
            <p class="indent">It can give information if a page is translated at the cost of sanity.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">5 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="rarity">unique</set>

        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Clippy, the Annoying Thieves Tool" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_TUNA_HomeBrew_MAGIC_ITEM_CLIPY">
        <description>
            <p> Crafted by Meeko the Devious, this artifact looks like a small bendy rod of iron with googly eyes and a mouth made of  clay attached to it.</p>
            <p class="indent"> You can strike it as an action, pointing it at an object within 120 feet of you that can be opened, such as a door, lid, or lock. The clip starts talking in a high pitch tone explaining you how to open the object,(potentailly alerting nearby enemies), and one lock or latch on the object opens unless the sound can't reach the object.</p>
            <p  class="indent"> If no locks or latches remain, the object itself opens. The item can be used 1 time per adventure, at dm's discretion.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="rarity">uncommon</set>

        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Jar of Beeholding" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_TUNA_HomeBrew_MAGIC_ITEM_JAR_OF_BEEHOLDING">
		<description>
			<p>This jar has an interior space considerably larger than its outside dimensions, roughly 2 feet in diameter at the mouth and 4 feet deep. The jar can hold up to 500 pounds, not exceeding a volume of 64 cubic feet. The bag weighs 15 pounds, regardless of its contents. Retrieving an item from the bag requires an action.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the jar is overloaded, pierced, or torn, it ruptures and is destroyed, and its contents are scattered in the Bee Plane. When the jar is turned inside out, the content is spilled out, and 5d6 x items*  bees come out, hostile to the party unless a Animal Handling Check with 10 DC is passed by the perpretator. Breathing creatures inside the bag can survive up to a number of minutes equal to 10 divided by the number of creatures (minimum 1 minute), after which time they begin to suffocate.</p>
			<p class="indent">Placing a <em>jar of holding</em> inside an extradimensional space created by a <em>handy haversack</em>, <em>portable hole</em>, or similar item instantly destroys both items and opens a gate to the Bee Plane. The gate originates where the one item was placed inside the other. Any creature within 10 feet of the gate is sucked through it to a random location on the Bee Plane. The gate then closes. The gate is one-way only and can't be reopened.</p>
            <p class="indent">Any wand put inside the bag is reduced to 1 charge. After the1 is used the wand is trandsformed automatically into a wand of bee swarm.</p>
            
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="15">15 lb.</set>
			<set name="stash" lb="500" weightless="true">true</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
    <element name="Ring of Singing, not Listening" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_TUNA_HomeBrew_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_SINGING,_NOT_LISTENING">
		<description>
			<p>A simple band made of meteoric iron. You gain a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls. In addition, you ignore half cover when making a spell attack.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Rings</set>
			<set name="type">Ring</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
			<set name="equippable">true</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		    <set name="enhancement">1</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>
    <element name="Night Caller" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_TUNA_HomeBrew_MAGIC_ITEM_NIGHT_CALLER">
		<description>
			<p>If you blow the whistle in darkness or under the night sky or under a black sun, it allows you to cast the animate dead spell. The target can be affected through up to 10 feet of soft earth or similar material, and if it is, it takes 1 minute to claw its way to the surface to serve you. Once the whistle has animated an undead creature, it can't do so again until 7 days have passed, unless the whitle was used in the negative energy plane.  ||Chose a part of your body. Your mouth moves there – it will return to normal once you blow the whistle.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
		</setters>
    </element>
	<element name="Silphium Leaf" type="Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_TUNA_HomeBrew_ITEM_SILPHIUM_LEAF">
        <description>
        <p>These dried leaves of the Silphium plant (extinct), when steeped to make a tea, can help a body recover from strenuous activity. If you drink a dose of Silphium tea during a long rest, your exhaustion level is reduced by 2 instead of 1 at the end of that long rest. You  are also under the effect of the mind blank spell for 24 hours during.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Potion of Greater False Life" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_TUNA_HomeBrew_ITEM_POTION_OF_GREATER_FALSE_LIFE">
        <description>
            <p>Your receive 2d4+4 Temporary Hit points and are resistant to necrotic damage for 24 hours. You are also an Undead for the duration with all the benefits and problem it causes.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            
			    <set name="cost" currency="gp">50</set>
			    <set name="category">Potions</set>
			    <set name="weight" lb="0.5">½ lb.</set>
			    <set name="type">Potion</set>
			    <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			    <set name="stackable">true</set>
            
        </setters>
    </element>
	<element name="Potion of Greater False Life" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_TUNA_HomeBrew_ITEM_POTION_OF_GREATER_FALSE_LIFE">
        <description>
            <p>Your receive 2d4+4 Temporary Hit points and are resistant to necrotic damage for 24 hours. You are also an Undead for the duration with all the benefits and problem it causes.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            
			    <set name="cost" currency="gp">50</set>
			    <set name="category">Potions</set>
			    <set name="weight" lb="0.5">½ lb.</set>
			    <set name="type">Potion</set>
			    <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			    <set name="stackable">true</set>
            
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Collar of Parking" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_TUNA_HomeBrew_ITEM_COLLAR_OF_PARKING">
        <description>
            <p>Requires attunement by a mount</p>
            <p class="indent">When a mount is attuned to the collar, you can insert gold coins in a slot on the collar and then speak the command word. If you do, the creature will be sent to a demiplane for an amount of hours equal to the amount of gold coins spent (1 gold coin = 1 hour). While in the demiplane, the creature does not need to breathe, drink, eat or sleep, and its hp cannot be increased nor reduced. As an action you can speak the command word to make the creature return.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			    <set name="cost" currency="gp">100</set>
			    <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			    <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			    <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Absolutely Legitimate Fabergè Egg of Enthralling" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_TUNA_HomeBrew_ITEM_Absolutely_legitimate_Fabergè_egg_of_enthralling">
        <description>
            <p>
            this beautul carved egg seems to be made of filigree platinum and emeralds,but on closer inspection it is revealed to be made of tin and green glass. As an action, you can throw the egg to a target you can see up to 60ft to impose disadvantage on all concentration check until the start of their next turn. When you do so, make a wisdom save DC 8: if you fail, you feel so bad for destroying such a precious work of art that have disadvantage on concentration checks and attack rolls until the end of your next turn. The item was made by the curse masters of Feli, the city of sorcerors – it is guaranteed to increase in power with the user. Once the egg is used, it will be hatched by an egglaying creature next to the attuned individual the next dawn.
            </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			    <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			    <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			    <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
                <set name="attunement">true</set>
			    <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Pipe of Smoke Shaping" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_GUCCI_HomeBrew_ITEM_PIPE_OF_SMOKE_SHAPING">
        <description>
            <p>A small, wooden pipe that feels smooth to the touch. While smoking this pipe, you can use an action to exhale a puff of smoke that takes any form. The form must be small enough to fit in a 1-foot cube and loses its shape after a few seconds, becoming an ordinary puff of smoke.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			    <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			    <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			    <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			    <set name="rarity">common</set>
            
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Tea Pot of Wonder" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_GUCCI_HomeBrew_ITEM_TEA_POT_OF_WONDER">
        <description>
            <p>A round, blue and white porclain teapot. Pours out unlimited tea, that lasts 5 minutes and disappears unless consumed. It behaves like ordinary tea when consumed.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			    <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			    <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			    <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			    <set name="rarity">common</set>
            
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Crossbow of Connection" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_GUCCI_HomeBrew_ITEM_CROSSBOW_OF_CONNECTION">
        <description>
            <p> A wooden crossbow with concave bowlimbs facing out. A ruby is engraved in it, above the trigger. You may chose to materialize a red, spectral rope at will, with anchor points being any bolts you've fired with this crossbow. You may materialize this rope between two fired bolts, and use it as a zipline, or leave one end of the rope dangling, like a swing. You may climb on the rope as if you have climbing speed equal to your movement. Only one rope may exist at a time, the maximum length of the rope is 60 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            
                <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous Items</set>
			    <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			    <set name="weight" lb="0">5 lb.</set>
			    <set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
                <set name="attunement">true</set>
                <set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			    <set name="rarity">common</set>
            
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Skaven Heavy Rifle" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_MIST_HomeBrew_ITEM_SKAVEN_HEAVY_RIFLE">
        <description>
            <p>Skaven Heavy Rifle.range 120/400 ft., one target. Hit: (2d8) piercing plus (1d6) necrotic damage. If the skaven heavy rifle misfires the turn after being repaired then it catastrophically fails in a bright emerald green explosion dealing 10 (3d6) force damage plus 7 (2d6) necrotic damage in a 5 ft. cube centered on it’s wielder. Misfire 5.  Loading property. You can take 30seconds to set up the scope to increase the range to 400/2000</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            
                <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			    <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			    <set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
                <set name="damage" type="piercing">2d8+1d6</set>
                <set name="type" addition="Firearm">Weapon</set>
                 <set name="weapon">Rifle</set>
			    <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
                <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			
            
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Quicksilver Rod" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_TUNA_HomeBrew_ITEM_QUICKSILVER_ROD">
        <description>
            <p>This featurless, silvery rod can transform in any martial or simple weapon as an action. If a ranged weapon is chosen, it transforms with 1 ammunition loaded. It  counts as magical for the purposes of overcoming resistances.
</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			    <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			    <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			    <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
                <set name="attunement">true</set>
                <set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			    <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Scarf of Sand" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_MIST_HomeBrew_ITEM_SCARF_OF_SAND">
        <description>
            <p>This scarf makes you immune to the effectives of sand storms and lets you create a mini sand storm in a 15 by 15 by 15 cube that has a dc13 con save to be blinded for one minuite. For an action the eyes can be cleaned out and you are immune for the duration. This can be used once per day.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			    <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			    <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			    <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
                <set name="attunement">true</set>
			    <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
<element name="Orb of Talking to Alimarj" type="Magic Item" source="Bleb March" id="ID_MIST_HomeBrew_ITEM_ORB_OF_TALKING_TO_ALIMARJ">
        <description>
            <p>
            this beautul carved egg seems to be made of filigree platinum and emeralds,but on closer inspection it is revealed to be made of tin and green glass. As an action, you can throw the egg to a target you can see up to 60ft to impose disadvantage on all concentration check until the start of their next turn. When you do so, make a wisdom save DC 8: if you fail, you feel so bad for destroying such a precious work of art that have disadvantage on concentration checks and attack rolls until the end of your next turn. The item was made by the curse masters of Feli, the city of sorcerors – it is guaranteed to increase in power with the user. Once the egg is used, it will be hatched by an egglaying creature next to the attuned individual the next dawn.
            </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			    <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			    <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			    <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
                <set name="attunement">true</set>
			    <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>

